(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
今日も大天才！
I'm a genius again today!
だーいてんさいっ！
A total genius!
大優勝！
Big Win!
大天才！
I'm a genius!
中毒！
Addicted!
今日も大天才！
I'm a genius again today!
だーいてんさいっ！
A total genius!
あ〜 ずっともっと
Ah, more and more,
推し事させてね
let me keep being your oshi.
今日はリリカの生誕祭ライブ！見に来てくれてありがとう！
Today is Ririka's Birthday Celebration Live! Thank you all for coming!
たくさんのゲストとオリジナル曲いっぱい歌うからね！盛り上がっていこー！
I'll be singing lots of original songs with many guests! Let's get fired up!
アクスタ 痛バ ぬい 準備万端！
Acrylic stands, itabags, plushies, all set!
オシャレも気合い入れちゃって
I've even put effort into my outfit.
「誰の為なの〜？」
"Who is it for?"
激エモ
Super Emotional
狙うことなき 推しの為 です！
It's for my oshi, without a doubt!
古参 新参も 人権は平等
Old-timers and newcomers all have equal rights.
内に秘めた 古参マウント
Hiding that "I've been here longer" flex.
Not 同担拒否 ですが
I'm not against sharing my oshi, but...
すごーし嫉妬はするかも…！
I might get a little bit jealous...!
尊い
Precious
いいねボタン足りません…
The "Like" button isn't enough...
これ無料でいいんですか！？
Is it really okay for this to be free!?
好き好きが募る 尊すぎるでしょ…
My love keeps growing, it's just too precious...
困っちゃうなあ
It's quite a problem.
今日も大天才！大天才！
I'm a genius again today! A genius!
出し惜しみ無理絶対考えたくもないなあ
Holding back? Impossible! I don't even want to think about it.
生き甲斐！
My reason for living!
お仕事は年中無休です
My work is 24/7, year-round
もう大天才 あ〜限界
I'm such a genius, ah, I've hit my limit
これ以上求愛されたら困ります
I'll be in trouble if you court me any more
だって召されちゃう
Because I'll be swept off my feet
だってせめてあなたがイチバンです！
Because, at the very least, you are the best!
予約した推しのフィギュア
The figure of my favorite I pre-ordered
“来年発送予定”
"Scheduled for shipping next year"
そんなの慣れっこです
I'm used to that kind of thing
忘れた頃に来るけど...!
It'll arrive when I've forgotten about it...!
溢れる才能 無量限界周波数ですが
My overflowing talent is at an infinite limit frequency
リリカダマシイ増えすぎる
Ririka-souls are increasing too much
らびゅー
Love you
あ〜もう好きっ！
Ah, I love you so much!
今日も大天才 大天才
I'm a genius today too, a genius
死ぬ無理待っててて
I'm dying, it's impossible, wait wait wait
考えられないや
I can't even think
尊死
Dying of wholesomeness
次の現場まで待てないや
I can't wait until the next event
もう大天才 あ〜限界
I'm such a genius, ah, I've hit my limit
切り詰めた生活 何一つ悔いじゃない
A frugal life, I don't regret a single thing
だってこんなにも 幸せ溢れた日々です
Because these days are just so full of happiness
来年も再来年も
Next year, and the year after
その先ずっと何年でも
And for many years after that
推していたい 好きでいたい
I want to keep supporting you, I want to keep loving you
でもあなたの幸せが
But your happiness is...
イチバン！
...number one!
無理だけはしないでね？
Just please don't push yourself too hard, okay?
あなたとあなたを見つけ出した
To you, and to the me who found you...
私にありがとうを
...I say thank you
今日も大天才 大天才っ！
I'm a genius today too, a genius!
なんでそんなに大天才？
Why are you such a genius?
困るよ完璧すぎるじゃん
It's troublesome, you're just too perfect
もう大天才 大天才っ！
I'm such a genius, a genius!
推し無し無理絶対考えたくもないなあ
Life without my favorite is impossible, I don't even want to think about it
生き甲斐
My reason for living
お仕事は年中無休です
My work is 24/7, year-round
もう大天才 あ〜限界
I'm such a genius, ah, I've hit my limit
これ以上求愛されたら困ります
I'll be in trouble if you court me any more
だって召されちゃう
Because I'll be swept off my feet
だってせめてあなたが一番
Because, at the very least, you are the best
推しに勝るものはなし
There's nothing that beats a favorite
我ららの空の始まりは
The beginning of our sky was...
触れた瞬間 あらららら
...the moment we touched, oh my my my
ホラこれは困った 2度と元に戻らない
Look, this is trouble, it'll never go back to the way it was
ダイバンパッ
Big Bang!
そして星が生まれまして
And then a star was born
明け方の一番星は
The first star of the dawn is...
あなたと出会った
...the moment I met you
これは次元を揺るがす大発見
This is a dimension-shaking discovery
このままハート撃ち上げて
Just like this, launch my heart up
どこまでも高い空まで
To the highest sky, wherever it may be
めちゃ飛んじゃいたい
I want to fly so high
Star Star Start 来たこのラブは
Star Star Start, this love that's come...
あなたでなきゃイマゴロ
...if it weren't for you, by now...
超新星
...it would have gone supernova
するぞ？しちゃうぞ！？
Gonna do it? I'm gonna do it!?
あなたに言ってますっ！
I'm talking to you!
今 Star Star Start
Now Star Star Start
あのわかってる？
Hey, do you understand?
ほら目の前にずっとある
Look, it's been right in front of you all along
一等星
A first-magnitude star
見てる 聞いてる
Looking, listening
このビッグバン気づいて
Notice this Big Bang
あぁ地球くらいに膨らんで
Ah, it's expanded to the size of the Earth
こんなになってんぞ
It's become like this!
そそそ大騒がせは
A little bit of a big disturbance is...
この時のためのスター
...the star for this very moment
あなたと
With you
わたしで
And me
ビッグバン したいの
I want to Big Bang
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ...
Na na na na...
愛は地球くらいに膨らんで
Love expands to the size of Earth
こんなになってんぞ
And has become like this
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ...
Na na na na...
三千世界の惑星は
The planets of the universe
このときのためにスタート！
Are starting for this moment!
ウッフー！
Woo-hoo!
フー！フー！
Fu! Fu!
リン・ドン リン・ドン 行動力
Rin-don Rin-don, proactiveness
ビビッドに期待を
Vividly, with expectations
もっと感じて
Feel it even more
リリカルMonster
Lyrical Monster
作詞：モナカカカ
作曲：森本 練
Lyrics: Monakakaka
Composer: Morimoto Ren
Enjoy もっと Enjoy
Enjoy, more Enjoy
リリカル・スイミング
Lyrical Swimming
上々 気分もっと
Exhilarated feeling, more
つよつよホームラン
Super strong home run
絶好調 真の才能
In top form, true talent
ヒエラルキーを見せてあげる
I'll show you the hierarchy
ラブリー・パーティー
Lovely Party
ドゥルン ドゥルン... 巻き起こる言霊台風
Drun drun... The rising spirit of words typhoon
もっと Happy
More Happy
とことんとことん駆けちゃうよ
Running and running to the very end
そうだろ こうだろ
That's right, like this
ときめきだろう
It's excitement, right?
L-L-Love いかがですか？
L-L-Love, how do you like it?
ちょっと ビビッと感じたなら
If you felt a little spark
止めらんない 止めどないくらい
Unstoppable, so much it's ceaseless
胸のドキドキ ドキ！
My heart is thumping!
一周回って現在進行形
One full circle, work in progress
グルグル追いかけっこ
Going round and round in a chase
あららら あらモード
Oh my, à la mode
このまま行くよ
Going on like this
リン・ドン リン・ドン 行動力
Rin-don Rin-don, proactiveness
ビビッドに期待を
Vividly, with expectations
もっと感じて
Feel it even more
Jumpin' Jumpin' ディスプレー
Jumpin' Jumpin' display
お邪魔します
Coming through
気分新鮮
Fresh feeling
タイムライン
Timeline
イロハローは認めません
I don't recognize Irohalo
史上最高の
The best in history
言霊マイスター
Spirit of words master
You and I ここから Ready
You and I, from here, Ready
ずっと見てて
Keep watching me
リリカルMonster
Lyrical Monster
ギラリ
Glare
リン・ドン
Rin-don
真っ向勝負かな
A direct showdown, maybe?
勢いブンブン
Vigor boom boom
もっと騒げ
Make more noise
Put your hands ブンブン
Put your hands boom boom
ダンスだけじゃない
It's not just dancing
もっともっと 褒めて
Praise me more and more
伸びて 絶好調
Grow and be in top form
バム バム... 突破レベル 脳内台風
Bam bam... Breakthrough level brain typhoon
やっぱ Crazy
As expected, it's Crazy
バシバシバシッ 鍛えちゃうよ
Slash slash slash, I'll train you
Give me love Give me love
ギルティ・ラブ・ガール
Guilty Love Girl
お代わりいかがですか？
How about another serving?
もっと 目に見て感じてよ
Look with your eyes and feel it more
やめらんない 目が離せない
I can't stop, I can't take my eyes off
君のハッシュタグ ハック！
Hack your hashtag!
もう一回回って通常運転
One more time around, normal operation
のびのびいつも通り
Carefree as usual
あららら あらカルト
Oh my, à la carte
このまま行くよ
Going on like this
リン・ドン リン・ドン 予測不能
Rin-don Rin-don, unpredictable
想像以上の 招待するから
I'll invite you to something beyond imagination
バンピン バンピン 下っ端に
Bumpin' Bumpin' to the underlings
妥協しない 百点
No compromise, 100 points
お代わりよ
Another serving!
朗読な中じゃありません
It's not just reading out loud
空前絶後の
The first and the last
言霊マジシャン
Spirit of words magician
Yes or Yes 何でも
Yes or Yes, anything
All right
一緒に信じて
Believe together
リリカルMonster マジ
Lyrical Monster, seriously
本当はね、リリカちゃんと二人で歌って踊ってみたいって思ってたんだけどね。
Actually, I was thinking that I'd like to sing and dance with Ririka-chan.
まさかこんな形で叶うなんて、誰が一番驚いてるって、団長だかんね！
I never thought it would come true like this. If anyone's surprised, it's the Captain!
ピントが違う時もあるよ
Sometimes the focus is off
そこがいいところ
That's what's good about it
どんな日も笑顔にする
Making a smile every day
宝物
A treasure
どんどん笑わす
Making you laugh more and more
相乗効果
Synergy
ニコニコ百万点
One million points for smiling
あららら ラブ＆ピース
Oh my, Love & Peace
このまま行くよ
Going on like this
まだまだ行くよ
Going more and more
ついてきてよね
Follow me, okay?
リン・ドン リン・ドン みんななら
Rin-don Rin-don, if it's everyone
リン・ドン リン・ドン できるはずさ
Rin-don Rin-don, you should be able to do it
リン・ドン リン・ドン 聞かせて
Rin-don Rin-don, let me hear you
リン・ドン・ドン 大きな声で
Rin-don-don, with a loud voice
リン・ドン リン・ドン 行動力
Rin-don Rin-don, proactiveness
ビビッドに期待を
Vividly, with expectations
もっと感じて
Feel it even more
Jumpin' Jumpin' ディスプレー
Jumpin' Jumpin' display
お邪魔
Interrupting
You are the happiness アロー
You are the happiness arrow
イロハローは認めません
I don't recognize Irohalo
史上最高の
The best in history
リリの笑顔だから
Because it's Riri's smile
ますますますラブ
More and more and more love
一緒に信じて
Believe together
リリカルMonster シュプリーム
Lyrical Monster Supreme
Yeah!
リン・ドン リン・ドン！
Rin-don Rin-don!
膝まずきなさい。
Kneel before me.
汝、この城の扉を叩いた者よ。
Thou who hast knocked on the doors of this castle.
誓いなさい。
Take thy oath.
このルーナの盾となり、矛となり。
To be Luna's shield and to be her spear.
夜はぐっすり眠れるまで、
Until you're fast asleep at night,
たまに甘やかすのらー！
I'll spoil you once in a while-nanora!
捧げなさい。
Offer it up.
捧げなさい。姫であると。
Offer it up. For I am a princess.
守ってルーナイト / 作詞・編曲：ナナホシ管弦楽団 / 作曲：岩見 陸
Mamotte Lunaight / Lyrics & Arrangement: Nanahoshi Orchestra / Composition: Iwami Riku
玉の座！
The throne!
どうなって？
How come?
紅茶のカップをカチャカチャ鳴らさないでえらい。
You're a good girl for not clinking your teacup.
スコーンだってこぼさず綺麗に食べてすごい。
It's amazing how you eat scones without crumbs.
たまに王冠どっちが前か間違っちゃうの、可愛い。
It's cute how you mistake which way the crown goes.
とってもよしなのお品なら、開場！
If it's to your liking, let the show begin!
ルーナイト第一章！
Lunaight Chapter One!
何よりルーナが好きだ人！
Those who love Luna more than anything!
ルーナイト第二章！
Lunaight Chapter Two!
シルクのお布団持ってきて！
Bring me my silk blankets!
ルーナイト第三章！
Lunaight Chapter Three!
三時のお茶会来れる人！
Those who can come to the 3 PM tea party!
守れなかったら即制裁！
Instant punishment if you can't keep them!
分かってほしいのら。
I want you to understand.
これも帝王学を学ぶため。
This is also to study the art of leadership.
愛という名の教育なのら！
It's education in the name of love!
守ってルーナイト
Protect me, Lunaight
想ってルーナイト
Think of me, Lunaight
プロムナード・ボイコット ななななら
Promenade boycott, na-na-na-na
手の甲にチュッ
A kiss on the back of the hand
おでこにチュッ
A kiss on the forehead
ガラスの靴履かせてワルツ
Put on the glass slippers and waltz
守ってルーナイト
Protect me, Lunaight
想ってルーナイト
Think of me, Lunaight
ブニョにキャンディ 台無しであってもね
Candy for the softie, even if it's ruined
君がいなきゃだって、皆。
Because without you, everyone...
心して、
Prepare yourselves,
捧げなさい。
And offer it up.
捧げなさい。姫であると。
Offer it up. For I am a princess.
ルーナってお菓子のあと、ちゃんと歯磨きするの、えらい。
You're a good girl, Luna, for brushing after sweets.
目覚ましなくたって起きられちゃうの、すごい。
It's amazing how you can wake up without an alarm.
ステップこんがらがっちゃったのも、可愛い。
It's cute how you got your steps all tangled up.
今日のお褒め言葉よしのなのら、開場！
Today's praise is to my liking, let the show begin!
ルーナイト第四章！
Lunaight Chapter Four!
ルーナを本気にさせる人！
Those who make Luna get serious!
ルーナイト第五章！
Lunaight Chapter Five!
ダイヤの原石積んできて！
Bring me a pile of rough diamonds!
ルーナイト第六章！
Lunaight Chapter Six!
ドラゴンペットにできる人！
Those who can tame a dragon as a pet!
つべこべ言わずに即実行！
No backtalk, just do it now!
きっと分かってくれるのら。
I'm sure you'll understand.
公序良俗読んだのら。
I read up on public order and morals.
恋はいつだって支離滅裂なのらー！
Love is always incoherent-nanora!
守ってルーナイト
Protect me, Lunaight
想ってルーナイト
Think of me, Lunaight
オペラハウス貸切なのななな
Renting out the opera house, na-na-na-na
角を抜いてチュッ
A kiss after removing the horns
制約書のチュッ
A kiss on the contract
ドレスの薔薇咲かせてロンド
Blooming roses on the dress for a rondo
守ってルーナイト
Protect me, Lunaight
想ってルーナイト
Think of me, Lunaight
バルコニーで待って、月にシュガー乗せちゃう
Wait on the balcony, I'll put sugar on the moon
あの子も綺麗だって、そんな。
That girl is pretty too? How dare you.
戯言はおやめなさい。
Cease your nonsense.
姫であると。
For I am a princess.
捧げなさい。
Offer it up.
姫であると。
For I am a princess.
特者生存ワンダラダー！！ / 作詞・作曲：田淵智也 / 編曲：佐高陵平 (Hifumi,inc.)
Tokusha Seizon Wander Ladder!! / Lyrics & Composition: Tabuchi Tomoya / Arrangement: Sataka Ryohei
行け！
Go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi-hi-hi!
南無三！おやおやもしもし！仕込み無罪で本日開廷
Namusan! Well, well, hello there! Not guilty, court is now in session
ザワッ、ボロッ、ギュムッ、バキッ、手にする全部イズマインフォーエバー
Zawa, boro, gyumu, baki, everything I hold is mine forever
適当に頑張ろう。
Let's do our best, somewhat.
そんなんでいいけどさ。
That's fine and all, but...
必死に頑張ろう。
Let's do our best, desperately.
それが僕ら仕様な。
That's how we roll.
出せ出せチャレンジャーじゃねーんだ
I'm not just some challenger
そんで貧乏くじじゃねーんだ
And it's not a raw deal either
うん、万事がバッチリ、イケてる自分に決まってる
Yeah, everything's perfect, I'm definitely cool
Are you gonna ダッチャー
Are you gonna daccha?
怒濤の前進状況ちゃんとちゃんと感知して
Properly perceive the surging forward progress
ワンダラダー！どこまで行くの？想像ちゃんと共鳴して
Wander ladder! How far will we go? Properly resonate with your imagination
ワンダラダー、どうしよう
Wander ladder, what should I do?
僕が選んだもの
The things that I have chosen
本当にするんだもん
I'll really do it,
現実超えろ未来　あー
Go beyond reality, to the future, ah...
逆境も平気　スイッチ連打
Adversity's no problem, spamming the switch,
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
即ち特者生存ワンダランダッデイ
Namely, the survival of the special, Wonder-la-der-day!
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
楽しもう
Let's have fun!
面白がれること探し魂オーヴァー
Searching for things to enjoy, soul going over!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer!
右左どっちじゃない
It's not about left or right,
決めつけていい属性
Any attribute you decide is fine,
ちなみたくなるなら発射
If you want to mention it, fire away,
ライダッ　ワクワクするぜ
Rider! It's getting exciting!
聴いて！
Listen!
推し引きちゃ　アイドルとっても楽しい
Drawing my oshi, being an idol is so much fun!
でもガチの結婚は立ち直れてません
But I still haven't recovered from that marriage!
ガチャが出るまで回せば100％ピックアップ
If you roll until you get it, it's a 100% pick-up rate!
パパ、天井です
Dad, I hit the pity limit...
なんだよ、そんなこと言っちゃダメ、おバカ！
What? Don't say things like that, you dummy!
賢い、ありがとう！
Smart! Thank you!
日々これ3000　レゴマイウェイ
Every day is like this, 3000... Let's go my way!
こうしたいだんてたいだもん　だって粋ガガいいだもん
I want it to be like this, because being stylish is good!
全方位にガッツリアンテナ張っていなくちゃ
I've got to have my antennas fully out in every direction!
いつでも心はジャスト純粋で
My heart is always just pure,
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
意外な好奇心は絶えず熱心で
Surprising curiosity is always earnest,
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
意外だって
Even if it's surprising,
言い聞かせるの
I'll keep telling myself.
調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうからああ
Because if I get carried away, they'll get bored quickly!
最高だろ　僕らどこまででも
It's great, isn't it? We can go anywhere!
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
即ち特者生存ワンダランダッデイ
Namely, the survival of the special, Wonder-la-der-day!
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
進化見つけ
Finding evolution,
努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Effort means not giving up until the very end.
メモっておいて
Take a note of that!
本当はベイビー自信ないよ
To be honest, baby, I have no confidence,
本当はベイビー不安ばっかで泣きそうだ
To be honest, baby, I'm full of anxiety and feel like crying.
でもねベイビー挫けないって決めたの
But you know, baby, I decided I wouldn't be discouraged!
だからベイビー挑戦したい未開の地
So, baby, I want to challenge the unexplored lands,
無限のフィールドで
In this infinite field!
ギター！
Guitar!
前進ちゃんとちゃんと確認して
Moving forward, checking properly, properly!
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
高みへ行こう想像ちゃんと共有して
Let's go higher, sharing our imagination properly!
興奮しよう
Let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん
Because I'm the one saying it,
本当にするんだもん
I'll really do it!
現実超えろ未来　あー
Go beyond reality, to the future, ah...
作戦も平気　スイッチ連打
The strategy is fine, spamming the switch,
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
即ち特者生存ワンダランダッデイ
Namely, the survival of the special, Wonder-la-der-day!
ワンダラダー
Wonder-la-der!
楽しもう
Let's have fun!
面白がれること探し放題ですぜ
There's so much to enjoy as much as we want!
無限のフィールドで
In this infinite field!
パニングしなくてもいいから
You don't even have to pan,
どんな無茶苦茶属性
Whatever ridiculous attribute it is!
ちなみにこれが僕の答えなんだ
By the way, this is my answer!
胸を張れ今を生きるその意味を
Stand tall, and the meaning of living in the now,
あくる日もあくるくる日も確かめ進め
Day after day, verify it and move forward!
おらよー！
Here we go!
はーい！できましたー！天音かなたちゃんありがとうー！
Yay! We did it! Thank you so much, Amane Kanata-chan!
はい！というわけで皆様！一条莉々華生誕祭ライブ2025にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Alright! So everyone! Thank you so much for coming to the Ichijou Ririka Birthday Live 2025!
ありがとうございますー！ありがとうございますー！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
いえーい！いえーい！いえーい！今日なんともう一人ね、呼んでいるのでMCを見たいと思います！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Today, we've invited one more person, so I'd like to bring them out for the MC!
こより先輩ー！
Koyori-senpai!
いえーい！こんこよー！一条莉々華ちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！
Yay! Konkoyo! Happy birthday, Ichijou Ririka-chan!
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much!
やったー！めっちゃ嬉しいです！来てくれてありがとうございまーす！
Yay! I'm so happy! Thank you for coming!
早速自己紹介させていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Could we start with the introductions?
もちろんです！
Of course!
やったー！本日の主役！可愛いポジティブジーニアスの一条莉々華よー！いえーい！
Yay! Today's protagonist! The cute positive genius, Ichijou Ririka! Yay!
大人になりました！
I've become an adult!
いや、なんかセクシーさに磨きがかかったんじゃないのー？
Wow, haven't you become even more sexy?
ムチムチですよ！ムチムチ！
I'm all curvy! Curvy!
大人になって！やったー！じゃあ先輩たちも自己紹介お願いします！
Becoming an adult! Yay! Now, senpais, please introduce yourselves too!
おす！はい！
Got it! Yes!
ヘイ！こんかなたー！キャッチコピーは握力50キロ！ぎゅぎゅっ！握りつぶしちゃうぞー！ホロライブ4期生、かなたんこと天音かなたです！
Hey! Konkanata! My catchphrase is "Grip strength of 50kg"! Squeeze squeeze! I'll crush you! Hololive 4th generation, Kanatan, also known as Amane Kanata!
ぎゅぎゅー！
Squeeze squeeze!
そしてー！はい、みんなこんこよー！ホロライブの頭脳、ジーニアス！博衣こよりだよー！
And! Yes, konkoyo everyone! The brain of Hololive, genius! I'm Hakui Koyori!
わー！私ジーニアスが取られるー！
Whoa! My "genius" title is being taken away!
奪っちゃったー！誕生日なのに奪っちゃったー！
I took it! Even though it's your birthday, I took it!
本当にありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
めっちゃ…なんか変な動きしてませんでした？
Wasn't I... making some weird moves?
いやもう面白いから、それやって…
No, it was funny, so do it...
こうやって…はっはっはっ…
Like this... haha...
両方にいるからね。両方見なきゃいけなかったんだね。
Because they're on both sides.
You had to look at both, right?
ありがとう、ありがとう、リリカ。ありがとうございますー！
Thank you, thank you, Ririka.
Thank you so much!
早速ね、ライブスタートしたわけなんですが…
So, the live has just started...
今回の配信のハッシュタグ！右上、こちら！
The hashtag for this stream!
It's right here in the top right!
ハッシュタグ一条莉々華生誕祭2025となってまーす！
#IchijouRirikaBirthdayCelebration2025!
Xでたくさんたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you could post a lot on X!
スクショとか感想とかモリモリ待ってます！
I'm waiting for lots of screenshots and impressions!
モリモリ待ってるからね！モリモリ〜！
We're waiting for lots! Lots of 'em!
ということでね、まずかなた先輩と特者生存ワンダラダー、歌わせていただきました！
So, first of all, I sang
'Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der' with Kanata-senpai!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
いやー、この曲本当に可愛くて、踊りもめっちゃね、可愛いし…
Wow, this song is really cute,
and the dance is also super cute...
嬉しい！こうやってね、ありがとう！
I'm so happy! Thank you for this!
もうめちゃくちゃ歌えて踊れて嬉しかったです！
I was so happy to be able to sing and dance!
こちらこそリリカの声でね、聴けて踊ってもらえて本当幸せでした。ありがとう！
Me too, I was so happy to hear it with Ririka's voice
and have you dance. Thank you!
ありがとうございますー！やったー！
Thank you so much! Yay!
そして、このあとね、こよりちゃん先輩とはあの曲を…
And after this, with Koyori-chan-senpai,
that song...
あの曲！歌わせていただきます！
That song! We'll be singing it!
どの曲なんだろう？あれかな？
Which song could it be? That one?
もうリリカの大好きな曲で…
It's a song Ririka loves so much...
本当に？あれ？なんかちょっとおかしいよ？
Really? Wait, something's a bit strange...
なんだこれ！なんか赤いよ！赤くなってる！
What's this! It's red! It's turning red!
え、え、大丈夫？なんか出てきたよ！
Wait, wait, is it okay? Something's coming out!
お化け？ゾンビ？ゾンビだ！
Ghosts? Zombies? It's zombies!
え、なになに、なんなん！わー！きゃー！
Eh, what, what is it! Whoa! Aah!
え、え、行け、リリカ、行け！リリカ、行け！
Wait, wait, go Ririka, go!
Go Ririka, go!
えー！リリカが！リリカ、頑張って！リリカ！
Noo! Ririka! Hang in there, Ririka! Ririka!
なんなん！これ！どうなっているのリリカ！
What is this! What's going on, Ririka!
わからない！え、待ってください、あそこに…
I don't know! Wait, look over there...
ゾンビ撃退クリームがある！
There's Zombie Extermination Cream!
なによそれ！取りに行こう！
What's that! Let's go get it!
ソフトクリームだよね？
It's soft-serve ice cream, right?
違います！これは、幻のクリームですよ。
No! This is the legendary cream.
説明役みたいな顔して言っちゃって。
She's saying it with an 'explainer' face.
これをゾンビに当てれば、多分ゾンビを…
If we hit the zombies with this, maybe we can...
多分？殲滅できるはず！殲滅してやる！
Maybe? We should be able to annihilate them!
I'll annihilate them!
行け行け！主役行け！リリカ見せろ！撃退しろ！
Go, go! Lead character, go!
Show us, Ririka! Fight them off!
あ！物理なんだ！えい、たあ！
Ah! It's physical! Take that! Hiyah!
いいぞいいぞ！リリカ！ちょっと、やばいやばい！
Nice, nice! Ririka! Wait, this is bad!
リリカがー！
Ririka—!
ふう…なんとかなりました。
Phew... we managed somehow.
危ない危ない。なんか格好いいところ出てたけどな。
Dangerous, dangerous.
Though you did show a cool side.
乗っ取りは完了ということで。
The takeover is complete.
え、乗っ取られてんの？ゾンビ大丈夫？
Wait, you're taken over? Are the zombies okay?
大丈夫です。あ、ホラ、戻ってきた！戻ってきた！
It's okay. Oh look, it's back! It's back!
よかったー！なんなんだこの茶番！全くわからなかったぞ！
Thank goodness! What was this farce!
I didn't get it at all!
一体なんなんだったんだよ、リリカ！
What on earth was that, Ririka!
いや、実はですね、ちょっとお化け屋敷感みたいなのを…
Well, actually, I wanted
a sort of haunted house feel...
せっかく遊園地だから、味わってほしいなって思って。
Since we're at an amusement park,
I wanted you to experience it.
えー！待って！ジェットコースターがよかった！
What! Wait! A roller coaster would've been better!
アトラクションみたいなね、お化け屋敷ね。
Like an attraction, right? A haunted house.
いや、でも、スモークは焚いてほしいって言ったんですけど…
Well, I did ask for smoke to be used...
まさかゾンビまで出てくるとは思わなくて。
I didn't think zombies would actually show up.
怖すぎるだろ！あんたの説明口調のやつもおかしかったぞ！
That's too scary!
Your explanation tone was weird too!
ソフトクリーム撃退者だったよね、あんた。食べられた、マウント。ソフトクリームだ！
You were the soft-serve ice cream repeller.
We got eaten, mounted. It's soft-serve!
ということでですね、まあ、このあとはこよりちゃん先輩と…
So, well, after this, with Koyori-chan-senpai...
歌わせて！この状態で！？
Let's sing! In this state!?
どういう心境でやればいいんだ。かっこよは。
What kind of mindset should I have? So cool.
いきましょう！
Let's go!
ということでかなた先輩、このあともちょっとここの遊園地でまったりゆっくりしててくださーい！
So, Kanata-senpai, please relax and take it easy
at this amusement park for a bit longer!
独りぼっちで楽しんでてー！
Enjoy being all alone!
ふざけんな！行ってきます！まったりでー！
Don't mess with me! We're off! Take it easy!
嘘でしょ？え、独りぼっち？
No way? Eh, all alone?
僕独りにさせられてるんだが。
I'm being left all by myself.
もう君の心チクッとしちゃえ
I'll make your heart sting a little
こよりちゃん先輩、来てくれてありがとうございます！
Koyori-chan-senpai, thank you for coming!
こちらこそ！いくぞー！
Me too! Let's go!
絶対無理思っちゃうし　だってだって不安になるし
I think it's absolutely impossible,
because, because I get anxious
全然嘘つけないし　だってだってわがままだし
I can't lie at all, because, because I'm selfish
目指すキラキラのきっと僕次第だ　ビターギブアップなんて言わないんだから
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me,
I won't say things like 'bitter give up'
じっとしてらんないし　だってだって動いちゃう足
I can't stay still, because, because my feet keep moving
ワンワンステップちょっとずつ進めば　夢の敷居溶けちゃうな
One-one step, if I move forward little by little,
the threshold of dreams will melt away
やりたい僕を　君が好きな僕を　ちゃんと余りなく見せたいな
The 'me' who wants to do it, the 'me' you like,
I want to show it all without leaving anything out
あっチャチャびっくりするほどできないんじゃ　間違って悩んだりばかりじゃ
Ah-cha-cha, if I can't do it surprisingly well,
if I'm just making mistakes and worrying...
見つけてほしくて
Looking for me,
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ
I'm coming to pick you up.
出会えたならハッピー
Meeting you is happiness.
わおっ！わおっ！
WAO! WAO!
お助けじゃえ
Help is here!
鳴いて 泣いて 愛して しっぽ振って
Howl, cry, love, and wag your tail!
わおっ！わおっ！
WAO! WAO!
お助けじゃえ
Help is here!
なめるな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Don't underestimate me, please remember me.
もう君の心チクッとしちゃえ
Let your heart feel a little sting.
もうどうしようとかたまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and feel down,
案外いけるかもふわり飛んじゃってもっとだーっと
But maybe you can do it, just fly away further and further.
べったりがやめられない
I can't stop being clingy.
おすわりってそれなんだっけ？
What was 'sit' again?
うっかりが止められない
I can't stop being careless.
またズンて壁に当たるの
I hit into the wall again.
わんわんステップアップ死んだふりしてるの
Wan-wan step up, I'm playing dead.
やめて はい こっちおいで
Stop it. Okay, come over here.
欲しがる君とあげすぎな僕とで
With you wanting more and me giving too much,
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go further.
あっ
Ah.
あっちゃっ ちゃっ
Oh my...
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
I'm surprisingly incapable,
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Always making mistakes and worrying.
手だっ
Give me your hand!
見つけてほしくて
Looking for me,
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ
I'm coming to pick you up.
出会えたならハッピー
Meeting you is happiness.
だって
Because...
やっぱり一人じゃダメだけど
Being alone is no good after all.
集まって馬鹿してわおっちゃえば
If we gather and goof around and 'WAO',
ほら いつでも言える「おかえり」
See, we can always say 'Welcome back'.
僕は君に伝えたいんだ大いなるハッピー
I want to convey to you this great happiness.
わおっ！わおっ！
WAO! WAO!
お助けじゃえ
Help is here!
鳴いて 泣いて 愛して しっぽ振って
Howl, cry, love, and wag your tail!
わおっ！わおっ！
WAO! WAO!
お助けじゃえ
Help is here!
なめるな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Don't underestimate me, please remember me.
目指す
Aiming for...
キラキラもきっと僕次第だ
Shining moments are surely up to me.
ピカピカなんてものはないんだからさ
Since there's no such thing as 'perfect',
メラメラでブチギレしないで
Don't get so heated and blow up.
はぐれずに希望へ大爆走
Let's dash together towards hope without getting lost.
君の心チクッとしちゃっていいじゃんハッピーちゃん
It's okay to let your heart sting a bit, Happy-chan.
常世の闇に囚われたまま 奏でる悲鳴を
While trapped in the eternal darkness, the screams played...
聞かせて
Let me hear them.
さあ爪を磨いたら まだ子供のようなあなたの為に
Now, once I've sharpened my claws, for you who are still like a child.
ああ試されたいなら その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
Ah, if you wish to be tested, put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に囚われたまま 甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
While trapped in the eternal darkness, I was chewing sweet, sweet gum.
いくつもの後悔をさあ捧げて
Come, offer up your many regrets.
何気ない合図に隠れて 答えはすぐに分からせてあげる
Hidden in a casual signal, I'll let you know the answer soon.
微かな嘘に塗れた 拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
Smothered in faint lies, I'll accept you even as you refuse.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせて
Now, let me hear your screams.
さあ指を鳴らしたら この子猫のような私の為に
Now, if you snap your fingers, for me who is like this kitten.
ああ喉が渇いたわ 薄紅の口に指を散らして
Ah, my throat is parched, scatter your fingers on my crimson mouth.
狭い牢屋に閉じ込めたまま 首輪に繋がれたいの
While locked in a small cage, I want to be bound by a collar.
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない 自由は既にこの手の中にある
Unimportant rules cannot take it away; freedom is already in these hands.
愛情では計れない 弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
It cannot be measured by affection, I'll let you choose while you're weakened.
ほら心を開いて
Now, open your heart.
分からないふりをして 寝ぼけてるの
Pretending not to understand, are you half-asleep?
もっと熱い暗闇見せて ねえ
Show me a hotter darkness, won't you?
何気ない合図に隠れて 答えはすぐに分からせてあげる
Hidden in a casual signal, I'll let you know the answer soon.
微かな嘘に塗れた 拒んだままに受け止めてあげる
Smothered in faint lies, I'll accept you even as you refuse.
常世の闇に刻むその名を 分からせてあげる
I'll let you know that name carved into the eternal darkness.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせてよ
Now, let me hear your screams.
夢見ないで ほら聞かせて
Don't dream, now let me hear them.
オーバーバード
Overbird
四六時中、乖離の海で 面倒くささを押し付けられてる 何から何まで
All day long, in the sea of dissociation, laziness is being pushed upon me. Everything from A to Z.
しごきはやめて まとめ役なら 聞き上手うなずき合ってる 仲良しこよしで
Stop the harsh training. If you're the mediator, be a good listener and nod along, all buddy-buddy.
さあ、だだだだ黙れだまりたまえよ
Now, be qu-qu-qu-quiet, please just shut up.
言えないねそんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I just want you to be a little bit quieter.
あ、私たち大望へ
Ah, we are heading towards a great ambition.
世界征服、ヤヤヤヤ果たすその日まで
World domination, ya ya ya ya, until the day it's fulfilled.
レレレ獄、ヤヤヤヤあなたの周りもヨヨヨヨ
Le le le prison, ya ya ya ya, even around you, yo yo yo yo.
世界征服、アレアレア約束の地まで
World domination, oh oh oh, until the promised land.
さあ、掲げよバッテンバッテン 伝染服ヤヤヤヤ
Now, raise the X mark. Infectious clothes, ya ya ya ya.
今日も嫌いそっちのけだね 嫌になるから私一人でも やっておきますね
Today too, you're ignoring what you hate. It makes me sick, so I'll do it by myself.
全て、全て、全て任せて それをさせてよ 大事な事なの 分かっているでしょう
Leave everything, everything, everything to me. Let me do it. It's important, you know that, right?
四六時中、乖離の海で 面倒くさいまま今日明日過ぎて行くのでしょう
All day long, in the sea of dissociation, being troublesome, today and tomorrow will pass by.
花瓶に水をあげましょう 時の中 しおれた事忘れてた
Let's water the vase. Inside time, I forgot that things had withered.
さあ、だだだだ黙れだまりたまえよ
Now, be qu-qu-qu-quiet, please just shut up.
言えないねそんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words.
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I just want you to be a little bit quieter.
あ、私たち大望へ
Ah, we are heading towards a great ambition.
今と未来見たかったはずなのに
Even though we should have wanted to see the present and the future.
世界征服、ヤヤヤヤ見えぬその日まで
World domination, ya ya ya ya, until the day it's invisible.
ドドドド永遠、ヤヤヤヤこの世の理ヨヨヨヨ
Do do do eternity, ya ya ya ya, the truth of this world, yo yo yo yo.
今は征服、ササササあなたの街中
Now it's domination, sa sa sa sa, throughout your city.
形作るバッテンだ
Creating the X mark.
世界征服、ヤヤヤヤ果たすその日まで
World domination, ya ya ya ya, until the day it's fulfilled.
レレレ獄、ヤヤヤヤあなたの周りもヨヨヨヨ
Le le le prison, ya ya ya ya, even around you, yo yo yo yo.
世界征服、アレアレア約束の地まで
World domination, oh oh oh, until the promised land.
さあ、掲げよバッテンバッテン 転覆したらヴィンテージのワインを空けましょう
Now, raise the X mark. If it's overturned, let's open a vintage wine.
はーーー！お疲れ様でしたーー！
Haa! Great job everyone!
ヒューーー！イエーイ！
Whew! Yay!
はい、ということで引き続きゲストパートお送りしておりましたが…
Alright, so we've been continuing with the guest part...
なんと、もう一人MCに呼びたいと思います！
And believe it or not, I want to call one more person for the MC!
誰だ誰だ誰だ？
Who is it, who is it, who is it?
トワ先輩ーー！
Towa-senpai!
イエーイ！！
Yay!!
来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
いやこちらこそ！
No, the pleasure is mine!
ちょっとせっかくなんで自己紹介して頂いてもいいですか？
Since you're here, could you please introduce yourself?
はい！オッケー！ホロライブ4期生の…
Yes! Okay! From hololive 4th gen...
あれ？うっそ？トワ様です！
Huh? For real? It's Towa-sama!
あれ？今「こんやっぴー」がないから言えないんだ
Huh? Since I don't have my 'Kon-yappi' right now, I can't say it.
こんやっぴーーー！
Kon-yappi!
はい、皆さん待たせたねー！ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
Yes, kept you all waiting! I'm the executive of holoX, Takane Lui!
莉々華、お誕生日おめでとうーー！
Ririka, happy birthday!
おめでとうございまーす！
Happy birthday!
めっちゃ嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
いや呼んでくれて嬉しいよ、お誕生日にさ
No, I'm glad you invited me for your birthday.
ありがとうございます！もうルイ姉もトワ先輩ももうすごい莉々華に優しくしてくれる…
Thank you so much! Both Lui-nee and Towa-senpai are always so kind to me...
もう莉々華的には姉御的な存在なので…
For me, you are like big sister figures...
まあまあ、慕ってくれて、慕ってくれて
Well, well, you look up to us, you look up to us.
あ、そこは謙遜しないのね
Oh, you're not being humble there.
お前もトワのこと慕えよ
You should look up to Towa too.
あー、トワ、トワ
Ah, Towa, Towa.
だからめっちゃ嬉しいです！イエーイ！
So I'm really happy! Yay!
やばい、このキラキラについていけない…
Oh boy, I can't keep up with this sparkle...
実は遊園地なんです！
Actually, it's an amusement park!
えー！めちゃめちゃ良い！最高！
Whoa! This is so good! It's the best!
最高のステージでしょ？でしょ？
It's the best stage, right? Right?
ジェットコースターもあるんだよね。
There's even a roller coaster.
そう！後で乗ろうよ。
Yeah! Let's ride it together later.
結構すごいスピードだよ！速い速い！
It's going really fast! Look at that speed!
ちゃんと乗れるようになってるんで、ぜひ！
It's built so you can actually ride it, so please do!
えー！後で一緒に乗ろうよ！
Whoa! Then let's ride together later!
乗りたい乗りたい！
I want to ride! I want to ride!
でも一旦、実は出店も用意してるので。
But first, I've actually prepared a stall for you.
よかったらこっちに来てください！こっちこっち！
So, please come this way! Over here, over here!
出店？何食べれるのかな？何のお店？
A stall? I wonder what we can eat? What kind of stall?
こっちです！こっちこっち！
This way! Over here, over here!
じゃーん！出店もありますよ！
Tada! I even have a stall!
すごーい！最高！
Whoa, awesome! The best!
なんかポツンとあるけど。
It's standing there all by itself.
ポツンじゃないでしょ！
It's not just standing there!
バルーンも付いてるんだよ！
It's got balloons too!
そうでしょ、可愛いでしょ？
That's right, isn't it cute?
ここでソフトクリーム食べれるんで。莉々華がいつもお世話になってる先輩たちに、
You can have soft-serve ice cream here.
And since you've always been so good to me,
莉々華がご馳走します！
Ririka will treat you today!
やったー！奢りですか！？
Yay! For real? It's on you?
もちろんです！
Of course!
さすが社長だよ！
As expected of the President!
食べましょう食べましょう！お腹空きましたね。
Let's eat, let's eat! It's getting late, after all.
じゃあいただきます！ありがとう！
Well then, let's dig in! Thank you!
わーすごい！おいしそう！
Whoa, it's so good! It looks delicious!
よかったら食べてください！
Please have some!
いただきまーす！
Digging in~
ありがとう。うまいわ！
Thanks. This is really good!
おいしー！サンキュー！
Delicious! Thank you!
あまーい！ねえ、めちゃくちゃ濃厚でうまいな。
So sweet! Man, it's really rich and tasty.
うん、いいソフトクリームだね。
Yeah, it's a great soft-serve.
よくアイス食べる？
Do you eat ice cream often?
食べる。
I do.
アイス大好き！
I love ice cream!
大好きですか？よかった！
You love it? That's great!
私ミルクが好きなんよ。ミルクが。
I especially love milk-flavored ones. Milk is the best.
ミルクうまいよね。
Milk is delicious, right?
私もね、このワッフルコーン大好きでよく食べるよ。
I also really love waffle cones, I eat them often.
ワッフルコーンいいよね！高級感あるわ。
Waffle cones are great! They feel fancy.
それはそう。バリバリがいいのよ、これの。
Right? The crispiness is the best.
莉々華はね、実はあんまりアイス食べないんですけど。
Actually, I don't eat ice cream that much...
食べないんだ？
You don't?
でも氷が好き！氷派！
But I love ice! I'm an ice person!
あ、氷派？今日クリーム系だけどね。
Oh, an ice person? We're eating cream today though.
しょうがないじゃん、クリームしか在庫がなかったんだもん！
Can't be helped! There was only cream in stock today!
いやいや、めちゃくちゃうまいです。ありがとう。
No, no, it's really delicious. Thank you.
ということで、ちょっと今回のライブステージも紹介させてください！
Now then, let me introduce this live stage as well.
じゃじゃーん！今回はなんと遊園地ステージとなっております！
Tada! This time it's the Amusement Park Stage!
すごーい！ロマンチックだね！
Whoa, amazing! It's so romantic!
ね、夜だからすごい綺麗だし。しかも！
Yeah, it's so beautiful at night. And look!
ジェットコースターが今登ってる！おおー！
The roller coaster is going up right now! Whoa!
乗りてー！めっちゃ速！
I want to ride that! It's so fast!
結構ドキドキするかもね。今来るの？みたいな。
It's pretty thrilling, isn't it? Like, 'Is it coming now?'
今？みたいなね。色々乗れるのもあるんで。
'Is it now?' sort of thing. There are various rides,
よかったら先輩たち、この後もまったりしていってください。
so please relax and enjoy yourselves later.
いいですか？じゃあ二人で乗ってね、ライブ見てるよ。
Really? Then let's ride together while watching the live.
こうやってアイス食べながら。映ったらごめんね！
Like this, while eating ice cream. If we're on screen, sorry!
どっかに映ってるかな？探そう探そう！
I wonder if we'll show up? Let's look for ourselves!
もう本当に、今日お二人に来ていただいてめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです。
I'm really, really happy you two could come today.
まず一個目が、莉々華、トワ先輩と『FACT』を一緒に歌わせていただいたんですけど。
First, I got to perform 'FACT' with Towa-senpai.
デビューした直後に、ReGLOSSでトワ先輩のライブを同時視聴させていただいて。
Right after ReGLOSS debuted, we did a watch-along of Towa-senpai's live.
その時に『FACT』聴いて、やべーめちゃくちゃかっけー！って思って。
When I heard 'FACT' then, I thought, 'Man, that's so cool!'
莉々華もこんな風に歌えるようになりたい、踊れるようになりたいって。
I wanted to be able to sing and dance like that too.
そんな興奮してくれたの？
You were that excited about it?
マジですよこれ！だから今回こうやって一緒に歌って踊ってもらえて、本当に嬉しいです。
I really was! So being able to perform with you today makes me so happy.
こちらこそ本当に一緒にできて嬉しかったよ。ありがとうね。
I'm happy we could do it too! Thank you!
素敵だった！奏とは『Overdose』を歌わせていただきました！
It was great! And with Kanade, we performed 'Overdose'!
『Overdose』もめちゃくちゃ好きな曲で、言ってくれてたもんね。
I love 'Overdose' so much. You said so too, right?
そうなんです！一緒に歌いたいなって、いつか、って言ってたのが夢が叶って、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
Yeah! I've always wanted to sing it with you.
My dream came true today, I'm so happy!
めちゃくちゃかっこよかった、ダンスも歌も。大人の色気ちゃんと出せてましたか？
The dance and singing were so cool.
Did I manage to show some adult charm?
出せてましたよ！大人の色気。素晴らしかったです。
You definitely did! That adult charm. It was wonderful.
やったー！嬉しい。やっぱ大人の色気ね、見せていきましたから。
Yay! I'm glad. We really showed our adult side, didn't we?
いかがだったでしょうか？なんでちょっと引いてるんですか！
How was it? Why are you backing away from us!
いや嬉しい、本当にありがとうございます！
I'm just so happy! Thank you so much.
まだまだ莉々華この後もあるので、ちょっとよかったらお二人から頑張れのエールを頂きたいです！
There's more to come, so if you could give me
some words of encouragement.
ソフトクリームももらったし、じゃあ二人でお礼のね、エールを。
Since we got ice cream, let's give her a cheer in return.
せーの、で言うね。せーの！
Ready? On three. One, two!
頑張れーーー！！
Go for it, Ririka!!
頑張れ！莉々華ーー！！ありがとうございます、頑張ります！
Go for it! Ririka!! Thank you, I'll do my best!
Break It Down
You made my day 憧れてただけ 待って 今は何も響かない
You made my day, I was just longing for it; wait, now nothing resonates with me
I know who I am
ブランディングに我慢 今は完全無視 お望み通り Greedy style
Enduring the branding; now I completely ignore it, just as you wish, Greedy style
ダサい僻みも興味ないの ありのままでいたい
I'm not interested in uncool prejudices; I want to stay as I am
Going my way 放っといて 止めらんない 熱に任せて
Going my way, leave me alone; I can't be stopped, leaving it to the passion
こりごりだろ Rule は break it down 我慢できない let me free
You've had enough, right? Break down the rules; I can't hold back, let me free
We are special でしょう揺るがないプライド それだけでいいの
We are special, right? An unwavering pride, that's all I need
たらればだらけの虚ろな日々を Break it down, break it down
The hollow days full of "what ifs"; Break it down, break it down
We are special でしょう誰に言われても 私は歌うよ
We are special, right? No matter what anyone says, I will sing
アンフェアばかりの世界など Break it down, break it down 進め
A world full of unfairness and such; Break it down, break it down, move forward
ハイテクなメイクやファッション Self-love には敵わないよ
High-tech makeup and fashion; they can't compete with self-love
包み隠さず 誰のものでもないでしょ
Not hiding anything; it doesn't belong to anyone, right?
いい加減いい大人だよね
It's about time, we're grown adults, right?
Inilah aku apa adanya Tidak sempurna tapi sepenuhnya diriku
This is who I am as I am; Not perfect but completely myself
でも今は楽しいよ ありのままでいられるから
But it's fun now; because I can stay as I am
Going my way 放っといて 止めらんない 熱に任せて
Going my way, leave me alone; I can't be stopped, leaving it to the passion
こりごりだろ Rule は break it down 我慢できない let me free
You've had enough, right? Break down the rules; I can't hold back, let me free
We are special でしょう揺るがないプライド それだけでいいの
We are special, right? An unwavering pride, that's all I need
たらればだらけの虚ろな日々を Break it down, break it down
The hollow days full of "what ifs"; Break it down, break it down
We are special でしょう誰に言われても 私は歌うよ
We are special, right? No matter what anyone says, I will sing
アンフェアばかりの世界など Break it down, break it down 進め
A world full of unfairness and such; Break it down, break it down, move forward
Going my way 放っといて 止めらんない 熱に任せて
Going my way, leave me alone; I can't be stopped, leaving it to the passion
こりごりだろ Rule は break it down 我慢できない let me free
You've had enough, right? Break down the rules; I can't hold back, let me free
次の曲は、SUPER DUPER！
The next song is... SUPER DUPER!
ReGLOSS で、SUPER DUPER！ 聴いてください！
With ReGLOSS, SUPER DUPER! Please listen!
目くるめく好奇心は森羅万象 行く末 神さえも知らぬ場所
Dazzling curiosity is all creation; The destination, a place even God doesn't know
混じり気のない情熱が 澄ました空虚を逆なでしたとこ
Where pure passion rubs against the cleared emptiness
寝静まる夜も とめどないアドバンス 猛烈な目まぐるしい時代も全部
Even in the dead of night, an endless advance; Even the intensely dizzying era, all of it
忘却の彼方へ笑い飛ばそう
Let's laugh it off to the far side of oblivion
Give me the, give me the beat right now!
SUPER DUPER 共鳴十色のシャングリラ 陽が暮れるまで踊ろうよ
SUPER DUPER, a Shangri-La of ten resonant colors; Let's dance until the sun goes down
誰が何と言おうと気にしない 未開拓
No matter what anyone says, I don't care; unexplored
衝動のリズムだけ 美しい声を響かせて
Only the rhythm of impulse; let the beautiful voices ring out
俯いた世界を 変えてみせよう
Let's change the downcast world
SUPER DUPER 今月今宵 満を持して形勢逆転 とっておき決める激アツ局面
SUPER DUPER, tonight, fully prepared for a turnaround; A super-hot situation to pull out the ace in the hole
転生しても もう一度ここへカムバック 純正そのものがセンセーショナルな漫画
Even if I reincarnate, I'll come back here again; Purity itself is a sensational manga
ビギナーから一躍 羽ばたいてオリジナル 一番目指し走り出す 血肉分けしジーニアス
From a beginner to a sudden leap, taking flight as an original; Starting to run for number one, a blood-related genius
巷を揺るがすポイズンサバイブ 打ち落としたって問題ない
Poison survive shaking the streets; no problem even if it's shot down
たぎりつく胸を 謳歌し止まないもの 疑うことも知らないまま
Something that never stops celebrating the burning chest; without even knowing doubt
さあ行っとけ 覚悟はできてるよ
Come on, go for it, I'm ready
Give me the, give me the beat right now!
SUPER DUPER 共鳴十色のシャングリラ 陽が暮れるまで踊ろうよ 誰が何と言おうと気にしない 未開拓
SUPER DUPER, a Shangri-La of ten resonant colors; Let's dance until the sun goes down, no matter what anyone says, I don't care, unexplored
限界以上
Beyond the limits
そっと楽しむだけ
Just enjoying it quietly
美しい声を響かせて
Letting my beautiful voice resonate
Yeay yeay yeay yeay Ah...
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you how I can change this downcast world
Yeay yeay yeay yeay SUPER DUPER
A-K-J-H-R
一期一会注いで
Pouring in once-in-a-lifetime encounters
一心同体でいて
Staying as one in body and soul
今宵なく 恋したメロディーと
With the melody I loved without ceasing tonight
会えなくて手放したレプリカ
And the replica I let go of because we couldn't meet
間もなく君との境界線を越えリセット
Soon, I'll cross the boundary with you and reset
SUPER DUPER 驚くほど
SUPER DUPER surprisingly
理想郷で弾けるまで踊ろうよ
Let's dance in Shangri-la until we burst
誰が何と言おうと 気にしないわ
No matter what anyone says, I don't care
限界以上
Beyond the limits
そっと楽しむだけ
Just enjoying it quietly
美しい声を響かせて
Letting my beautiful voice resonate
Yeay yeay yeay yeay Ah...
俯いた世界を変えてみせよう
I'll show you how I can change this downcast world
Yeay yeay yeay yeay SUPER DUPER
というわけで、ReGLOSSでSUPER DUPERお送りしましたー！
And so, that was SUPER DUPER performed by ReGLOSS!
みんな来てくれてありがとー！
Thank you all for coming!
もうさっきもやったんだけど、もう一回やってもいい？
We already did it earlier, but can we do it once more?
あ、うん。いつでもできます。
Oh, sure. We're ready whenever.
リーチザトップ！ We are...
Reach the top! We are...
ReGLOSS!
せっかくだからちょっとみんなに自己紹介して欲しくて。じゃあ奏から！
Since we're here, I'd like everyone to introduce themselves. Let's start with Kanade!
はーい！えっと、一条莉々華の恋人、音乃瀬奏でーす！
Hi! Um, Ichijou Ririka's lover, Otonose Kanade here!
おー、おいおいおい。
Whoa, hey hey hey.
いつの間に？いつの間に恋人だったんだ。
Since when? Since when were we lovers?
莉々華大好きだよー！
Ririka, I love you!
やったー！
Yay!
え、一条莉々華にゃの... ぺっちょ。
Uh, Ichijou Ririka-nyan's... pet.
へ、ペット！？
Wha, a pet!?
わんわんわん！ ...あつあつあつ。
Woof woof woof! ...Hot hot hot.
えー、じゃあ、一条莉々華の、えー配信デスクの上のタンブラーを置くあのコースターみたいなやつ、儒烏風亭らでんです。
Um, well, the coaster-like thing under the tumbler on Ichijou Ririka's streaming desk, Juufuutei Raden here.
なにそれは一体。キモいっちゃや。
Wh-what is that even? That's gross.
ずっと一緒や。
We're always together.
あ、ずっと一緒。そういうことか。
Ah, always together. I see.
えー、みんな来てくれてまじでありがとねー。
Everyone, thank you so much for coming.
誕生日だっけ？なんの日だっけ今日。
Was it a birthday? What day is it today again?
祝いに来たんだろ！
You came here to celebrate!
そうです。莉々華、大人になります。お誕生日です！
That's right. Ririka is becoming an adult. It's my birthday!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
いや、誕生日っていいな、毎日誕生日がいい。
Man, birthdays are great. I want it to be my birthday every day.
毎日年取ることになるけど。
You'd age every day then.
じゃあこの話は終わりということで。置いといてね。
Well, let's end this topic. Put it aside.
はい、じゃあここからはね、ちょっと告知をさせていただきたいなと思っております。
Okay, from here, I'd like to make some announcements.
告知ー！
Announcements!
もしかして、一条莉々華誕生日記念2025グッズが出るってこと！？
Could it be that Ichijou Ririka Birthday 2025 goods are coming out!?
じゃあこちらをご覧ください。ドン！ジャジャーン！
Then take a look at this. Boom! Ta-da!
可愛いー！
So cute!
俺の莉々華！
My Ririka!
好き好き好き！尊い。
Love it, love it! So precious.
じゃあこちらね、もう初めての生誕祭のグッズということで、盛りだくさんのグッズになっております。
So these are my very first birthday goods, and there's a lot of them.
今回はですね、イラストはトマリ先生に描いていただきました。本当にありがとうございます！
This time, the illustration was drawn by Tomari-sensei. Thank you so much!
可愛くて美しくて最高だよね。
It's cute, beautiful, and just the best.
じゃあちょっと詳細も見ていきたいと思います。まずは、こちら！
Now let's look at the details. First, this!
はい、えーまずは、アクリルスマホスタンドです。
Yes, first is the acrylic smartphone stand.
今回ね、オリジナル衣装で歌って踊ってる莉々華の描き下ろしイラスト... はい、してもらいました。
I had an original illustration made of Ririka singing and dancing in her original outfit.
でもめちゃくちゃ本当に可愛いし、もうね、アクリルスマホスタンドなので、スマホを上に置けるということ。つまり、ずっと一緒にいれるということ。イエーイ！
It's really, really cute, and since it's an acrylic smartphone stand, you can put your phone on it. Meaning we can be together forever. Yay!
欲しいー！
I want it!
大事に使ってください。そして、続いてはこちら！ドン！
Please use it carefully. And next is this! Boom!
ランダムラバーストラップ。ま、やっぱりね、莉々華、あの、オタクなので自分自身も、何しようかなって考えたときに、ラバスト欲しすぎー！と思って。
Random rubber straps. Well, since I'm an otaku myself, when I thought about what to make, I was like, "I want rubber straps so bad!"
今回ね、あの、上倉エク先生に4種類もの莉々華を書き下ろしていただきました。めっちゃ可愛い。ありがとうございます！
This time, Uekura Eku-sensei drew four different types of Ririka. They're so cute. Thank you!
あ、悪役令嬢なの？
Oh, is it a villainess?
そうだよ、悪役令嬢の莉々華もいます。
That's right, there's a villainess Ririka too.
うわー！莉々様！莉々様！
Whoa! Riri-sama! Riri-sama!
莉々様だっけ？そう、莉々様。莉々様ですわ！
Was it Riri-sama? Yes, Riri-sama. It's Riri-sama!
ね、無理しました今。
Yeah, I pushed myself there.
で、こちらは、えっと、ランダムで1種類封入されております！
And this one is, um, it contains one type at random!
おー！
Oh!
そして、続いてはこちら！
And, moving on to the next one!
ウニペンケース！
Uni-pen Case!
ふわっふわでね、もうめちゃくちゃ可愛い、もう...
It's so fluffy and really cute, just...
お腹裂かれてる？
Is its stomach split open?
お腹じゃなくて背中ですね。背中、背中。
It's not the stomach, it's the back. The back, the back.
背中は裂いてますが、まぁ、内臓がペンみたいな感じでね。
The back is split, well, it's like its internal organs are pens.
なるほど、なるほど！
I see, I see!
可愛がってあげてください。普段使いできるのでぜひぜひ使ってください。
Please take good care of it. You can use it daily, so please do.
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
なんと限界飯プレートが出ます！
Believe it or not, a Genkai Meshi Plate is coming out!
かわいい！お米すごい！
Cute! The rice is amazing!
そう、これね、あのお米が敷いてあるようなイラストのプレートなので、
Yeah, this is a plate with an illustration that looks like rice is spread out on it,
もうこの上にね、具材を乗せれば簡単お手軽に限界飯が作れるという優れものになっております！
so if you put ingredients on top of this, it's a great item for easily making 'genkai meshi'!
いいじゃん！かわいい！
Nice! Cute!
そしてウニもちらっと書いてある。
And Uni is also drawn a little bit.
そう、ウニもいますよ。
Yeah, Uni is there too.
ありがと！じゃあ続いてはこちら！
Thanks! Okay, next up is this!
まぁね、ボイスもやろうかなっていうことで、
Well, I thought I'd do voices as well,
今回みんな待望のASMRボイス収録しております！やったー！
and this time we've recorded the long-awaited ASMR voices! Yay!
1個目は、莉々華の部屋で一緒にゲーム、で、
The first one is 'Playing games together in Ririka's room',
まぁ莉々華のね、おうちで隣でなんか一緒にゲームをしてるかのようなラブラブボイスとなっておりますので、よろしくお願いします！
and it's a lovey-dovey voice that makes it feel like we're playing a game together right next to each other!
いいえ！買うしかない！
No way! I have to buy it!
そしてなんとですね、フルセットの購入特典もございます！こちらです！
And surprisingly, there are also benefits for purchasing the full set! Here they are!
はい！まずは、直筆サインがついてきます！
Yes! First of all, it comes with a hand-signed autograph!
で、こちらはですね、もう莉々華限定とかじゃなくて、買ってくださった方には全員にお付けしたいと思っているので、
And for this, I want to give it to everyone who buys it, not just a limited number for Ririka,
ぜひいっぱいっぱい購入してもらえると嬉しいです。ポストカードに直筆サインをつけてお渡しします。
so I'd be very happy if a lot of people buy it. I'll give it to you as a postcard with a hand-signed autograph.
でもう一つが、さっきASMR1個目はって言ったんですけど、2個目がこちらで、
And another one... I said 'the first ASMR' earlier, but the second one is this:
「あなたの誕生日をお祝い」ということで、今回ね、まぁ今日は莉々華の誕生日をみんなにこうやってお祝いしてもらってるわけですけど、
'Celebrating Your Birthday'. Today, everyone is celebrating Ririka's birthday like this,
莉々華もみんなの誕生日をお祝いしたいと思って今回準備しました！ぜひ自分の誕生日に聞いてください！
but Ririka also wants to celebrate everyone's birthdays, so I prepared this! Please listen to it on your own birthday!
はい、じゃあ改めてフルセットはこちらとなります！
Okay, so once again, here is the full set!
じゃーん！いやなんて豪華なんだ、あまりにいっぱいありすぎて。ねぇもう絶対に買ってください！絶対に絶対に！よろしくお願いします！
Ta-da! Wow, it's so luxurious, there's just too much. Please buy it! Absolutely! Thank you!
そしてさらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
And furthermore, as a full set benefit for the Talent Premium Goods,
去年から発売されているホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで、なんと使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game, which has been on sale since last year, is included!
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみが対象となります。
The card is only available to those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典につくのは推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンのカードです。
The benefit is a key card that lets you show off your 'oshi', an Oshi-Holomen card.
カードの詳細や遊び方などについてはホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the website for card details and how to play.
なんと実はまだお知らせがあるんです！こちらをご覧ください！
Actually, there's still more news! Please take a look at this!
じゃーん！出た！よしよしよし！一条莉々華のLINEスタンプの制作が決定しましたー！
Ta-da! There it is! Yes, yes, yes! It's been decided that LINE stamps for Ichijou Ririka will be produced!
詳細はね、後日公開となりますので、ご確認のほどよろしくお願いします。
Details will be released at a later date, so please stay tuned.
めっちゃ可愛くない？やばすぎるでしょ。いっぱい使ってください！
Aren't they so cute? They're amazing. Please use them a lot!
以上、一条莉々華生誕祭記念ライブのグッズ情報でした！みんな買って頂けるととても嬉しいです！
That's all for the merchandise info for the Ichijou Ririka Birthday Live! I'd be very happy if everyone buys them!
改めにはなるんですけど、もう本当にこうやってね、今回ライブ生誕ライブ、無事やることができて、もうめちゃくちゃ嬉しい気持ちでいっぱいです。
To repeat myself, I'm just so happy that I was able to successfully hold this birthday live like this.
たくさんの応援、コメント、もう常日頃から莉々華にいっぱい届いております。
I receive so many cheers and comments from everyone every single day.
みんなが応援してくれたおかげで、また莉々華ダンス頑張れた！歌も頑張れた！
Thanks to everyone's support, Ririka was able to work hard on dancing and singing again!
これからもたくさんたくさんみんなといろんな景色見れるように頑張りますので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll continue to do my best so that I can see many different sights with all of you, so please keep supporting me!
ってさ、あれ？
Wait, huh?
リグロス...どこ行った？消えた？
ReGLOSS... where'd they go? Did they disappear?
えっ、なんで？どこー？
Eh, why? Where are you guys?
莉々ー、こっちだよー！あっちあっち！
Riri, over here! That way, that way!
いたー！もう、あんなところに！
Found you! Jeez, in a place like that!
メリーゴーランドに乗ってたのかー！あーもう楽しそう！
You were on the merry-go-round! Ah, you look like you're having so much fun!
楽しそう！
Looks like fun!
白馬の王子様みたいになってるじゃん番長。
Bancho, you look like a prince on a white horse.
どうだろ、どうだろ。パカラパカラ。
Right? Right? Clip-clop, clip-clop.
いいなー。莉々華も乗りたい気持ちはもういっぱいあるんだけどさ、
Nice. Ririka really wants to ride it too, but...
このあとまだアンコールライブもあるから。
...we still have the encore live after this.
ごめんね、これ3人用なんだわ。
Sorry, this is only for three people.
いやいやいや、こんなに席あったのに、3人用だったんだこれ！そうなの？4人乗ったら止まっちゃう？止まっちゃう？重さで？
Wait, wait, wait, there were so many seats, but it's only for three people?! Will it stop if four people ride? From the weight?
莉々華が...莉々華の体重のせいで...
Because of... Ririka's weight...
まぁなんか言ってますけれどもね、このあと莉々華満を持してアンコールライブがあります！
Well, they're saying things, but after this, Ririka will finally have the encore live!
おー、頑張れ！
Oh, do your best!
アンコールライブでは、ホロライブのあの曲やあの曲を歌っちゃおうかなー！
In the encore live, I might sing that song or that song from hololive!
…持ってるので 楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
...I have [more planned], so I'd be happy if you enjoy it!
なおさってー！
Naosatte!
じゃあみんな、今日来てくれて本当ありがとね！
Well then everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
この後もゆっくり楽しんでね。バイバイ！
Please enjoy the rest of the show. Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！ありがとうー！
Bye-bye! Thank you!
大好きな秘書みならいへ
To my beloved apprentice secretaries,
苦手だった歌やダンスをがんばりたいって
Being able to want to work hard on singing and dancing, which I used to be bad at,
思えるようになったのはみんなのおかげだよ。
is all thanks to everyone.
これからも ずっとそばで 応援してくれる？
Will you continue to support me by my side forever?
変わらない毎日と
With unchanging everyday life,
新しいチャレンジを一緒に...
and new challenges together...
ホロライブに入れてよかった！！！
一条莉々華
I'm so glad I joined Hololive!!!
Ichijou Ririka